Release group MANIA presents
http://doramamania.mybb.ru
http://vk.com/doramamania
Episode 17
You said that as long as we are together, you don't need to be an emperor
Don't you say that anymore
We agreed not to lie to each other
I started this, I have to stop the brothers from killing each other
But...
Project coordinator, editor, typesetter and song translator: Nemie
When I was building the palace,
I realized that the world can change if the ruler who rules it changes
Translators: Nemie, tamaramin, Kaia
I don't want to be controlled
And I can get rid of all this absurdity
Beta Editor: Sana
Become an emperor -
what I want
What? Don't you want me to become emperor?
I don't like it
But most of all I don't like being away from you
Thank you
You will become the emperor
I know
But you should never...
Brothers should never be killed
Can you promise?
March 949
This is Prince Wang So!
The army is approaching!
Close the palace gates!
Are you...hiding something from me?
Did you poison the tea or something?
No, Your Majesty
The court lady has already checked it
Now, being in this state, I thought about everything
and realized that it all started with you
What?
Older brother, Eun, Eun's wife
Even the late emperor
All these dead people are getting to me
It's your fault
I decided to kill my brothers and become emperor
All because of you...
You helped Seo hide his scar so he could take my place.
Because he took what belonged to me...
Your Majesty!
Yo!
It's So! So is heading to the palace!
Wang So... started a rebellion!
Yo, Yo...
Write quickly
Write that you are transferring the throne to Jeong
Rather
What?
We can't lose our throne
Rather. Write that Jeong will become the new emperor
Then we can plan for the future. Come on
But... what about me?
Am I your son?
Who am I to you, mother?
Something that should sit on the throne?
You no longer need a son who has ceased to be an emperor?!
Yo, don't be like that
We'll lose everything if you behave like this.
Please give it to Jeong
Now I think I understand So
I can understand his feelings
Bring out the Empress Dowager!
Yo
Yo, don't do this! Yo! Yo!
Yo! Let me go! Release immediately!
Let go. Yo!
Yo!
Let go! Let me in! Yo!
I can't find my brother
Park Soo Kyung and Seo...
The palace guards won't last long...
Mother?
Whatever you decide, I will go with you
I realized this when I saw your brother
I realized that I forgot to teach you
If you want to become the owner of a palace, you need to sacrifice something
Mother
Decide for yourself
You can take over the whole world, but lose love
You can love, but live in a very small world
What if I want the whole world?
I... will give up Uka
I will attack the palace that I have always defended
I will help you enter the palace without bloodshed
I won't forget your loyalty
I knew that in the end he would get everything
What did I... do wrong?
I was afraid that they would get rid of me too
Like from So
I thought they would turn away from me
Mother told me
She said I have no flaws
But...
It's all because of you, girl!
Because of your interference!
You must choose
Who should I give the throne to?
Choose
Uku?
Baek A or So?!
You're so experienced, why don't you choose?
Find the Emperor! Alive!
- Eat!
I just
tried to survive
Have you read this?
To the side!
Get away, I say! Away!
Yo...
Hail the new emperor
Long live... Long live...
emperor
What does "emperor" mean?
What does it mean?
His Majesty gave me the throne before his death
He handed it to me
What?
Greetings, Your Majesty
- Hail to the Emperor
- Long live the emperor!
His Imperial Majesty!
Gwangjong
He is the 4th Emperor of Goryeo
Now you won't be recorded
in history as a "bloody ruler"
I will help you
Now our Hwangbo clan is using
its power to promote the empress
It makes me sad to see how much you've changed
The more you go astray, the more you will suffer
It's better for you to distance yourself from the imperial family
Why didn't you come to the coronation?
What if people don't think so?
When I arrived in Seogyeong, Wang Sik Ryeom was already dead.
I immediately sent a message asking to find the 4th Prince's people,
but the owner of the throne has already changed
The rebel who breaks the one who committed treason becomes a hero
I wanted this place, but Wang So took it
You wanted me to see this
Isn't this too cruel?
Help me
I will become an empress and thank you for the pain you went through.
I will take away part of your burden that you have been coping with alone for so long
Give me strength, brother. Please
Change of capital...
Issue an imperial decree that the change of capital will be stopped immediately
All people forced into construction
will receive payment in accordance with the duration of their work, everyone will return home
What about those who died?
Do what their families ask
Promise them jobs, compensate them with goods
Then... have we discussed everything for today?
Yes
Your Majesty,
Courtier Hae from Damiwon is waiting for you
Hae Soo?
I only remember your smell and your laughter
I'm always waiting only for you, counting the days
And it doesn’t matter where I am now, because only you are in my thoughts
What I dreamed about and what I wanted
Do you know what? Don't you know yet
Su
I just want to meet you
Yes, I want to admit that I'm waiting for you
Have you come?
And every day I can shout “I love you,” so what?
And every day I can call you
How long did you wait? I'm sorry
My heart is trembling so much, will you hear it?
Here...
Now, you like this, right?
I love, I love, I love
Thank you very much, Your Majesty
What are you doing? Everyone's here
Call me brother
I don’t know about others, but you can
Yes, Your Majesty
"Your Majesty" again?
Thank you very much, Your Majesty!
Sit down, sit down
Great, I really like it
I was so looking forward to you and I having dinner together,
like a family
Yes, we understand, please eat
If you talk to me on an empty stomach,
I won't eat with you anymore
Okay, let's get started
Su!
I thought you were gone
I'll leave when you fall asleep
It's been a long day
Why go back and forth?
Just sleep with me
Because I'm next to you, I'm very happy
Because I'm next to you, I keep dreaming
What?
Because I'm next to you, I smile so brightly
You have become an emperor
I don't want bad rumors to start
I'll be back tomorrow
For you to be mine, I always pray to the Gods
I need you here
If you see my love and my feelings
I feel uneasy here
Perhaps because he saw the death of the previous owner of the chambers?
If you find my love and the path to me
Thoughts that I will be here alone
suffocating me from the inside
I will give my heart completely
Stay, eh?
Stay with me
If you can stay with me for the rest of your life
Can you tell me a story?
We're not very far from a thousand
You won't see stars from here
Maybe tell a story about you?
About me?
The big and terrible wolf ate a girl named Little Red Riding Hood
I want to love you like my last love
Once upon a time
Once upon a time there was a cute little girl
If only everything were like this, then life would be happy
with big eyes,
Mom sent her to take it to her grandmother...
I will give my heart completely
If you can stay with me for the rest of your life
I'm with you
All with you
Even after just a day
I realized how naive I was
It's hard to wait for him, even though I want him to become emperor
However, I think I can wait even longer
Be careful with words like that
The Emperor is married to Princess Gyeong-hwa, but she will become a priestess
The empress's seat is still empty
People will be watching you closely, so be careful.
Senior courtier! Senior courtier!
Chae Ryung, you...
Concubine He, Empress Dowager Yu wants to see you
Greetings, Your Majesty
I called you because I have a question
Jeong
This was found in the room of the late emperor
It seems like this is his last decree
I'm sure we're talking about the transfer of the throne
If so, it may not be So's name listed here
Tell me
Did the late emperor really want to hand over the throne to So?
Don't be afraid, we will protect you
You just need to be honest
Is it true that the late emperor wanted to hand over the throne to So?
Yes it's true
Lies, you're lying
I know Yo
Nobody knows him better than me
He would never have handed over the throne to So
Tell me! Tell the truth!
- Mom
- Tell me, tell me!
- Tell!
- Stop!
That's enough
You can ask me this, why are you bothering her?
How's that?
Then why don't you tell me the truth?
Why did you tear up the decree?
Who said it was me who tore it?
I don't know why Yo tore it
and left only a dying wish
He handed over the throne to me, there can be no doubt about it
He has a son. Why should he
handing over the throne to your younger brother?
If you're so curious, maybe you could ask him in the afterlife?
It's good that he abdicated the throne
How would things turn out if we had to seize the throne?
I think around this time
the palace would be filled with Jeong's blood,
my brothers and nephews
Empress Dowager, why aren't you preparing a memorial service for the late emperor?
I will visit you more often
inquire about your affairs
Don't call me Empress Dowager
I don't want to be called that because you sit on the throne
But I am also your son, mother
If your son is an emperor, you become empress dowager
You are just a thief who stole my son's throne!
Tell my clan in Jeonju that I want to see them
You don't have to go anywhere, even if they call you
Okay
No matter who it is, no matter what title, you must first get my permission.
Do you understand?
I understood
I...
Your Majesty, rumors are coming to us from all sides
What rumors?
People believe that Gyeong Jong Won Geun should be the emperor
Foreign Minister Park Yong-gyu thinks you lied about the emperor's dying wish
Kill
What?
Kill everyone who accuses me of treason
Servants of the late emperor...
We need to take care of all the court ladies and guards who were in Jeongdeokjeong.
Don't leave a single person behind
which casts doubt
my right to inherit the throne
Don't miss out
none
The Emperor is determined to catch me
It was you who started the rumors that the emperor lied about the dying words of the late emperor
Did you think you'd be safe?
What is it?
Then I better reveal the fact
that you were spying on the 4th prince and Baek Ah
Do you think I'll die alone?
Clueless girl
I haven't seen this for a long time
It's gotten pretty dirty, you need a new bag
I don't want to lose him
Did you get it from your parents?
I'll have to do something
whatever your parents don't like
What is this?
Before our marriage,
I think we need to arrange for you
adopted daughter into a good family
Is it because I'm from Hubaekje?
My grandmother still remembers what happened in Gyeonghwan
Her family was killed before her eyes
She tries to avoid any dealings with people from Hubaekje
But it happened before we were born
What does this have to do with you?
You are Gyung Won's granddaughter
Still, I would like to avoid unnecessary problems
I will visit your parents at the cemetery and ask for their forgiveness.
If someone finds out about your relationship,
Prince Baek Ah will also be in danger
Is everything okay?
Emperor Goryeo killed my parents
and our king killed yours
Do you think we can be together?
Woo Hee
It's not my fault
and not yours either
Think about us
Until you stop loving me
we will never be apart from you
I'm against it
I want to relax, so I'll go back to my hometown
I need you more than ever
I don't understand why you insist on leaving
To tell the truth...
I'm incredibly tired of the imperial court
Every time I walk from side to side...
My girl...
I see my girl, I hear her voice
I try my best to pretend it's not true
But I can't get rid of your image with a sword in your hands
It's very difficult
Don't leave
- Don't leave
- Your Majesty
For the sake of this country and its people
become a good and wise emperor
You must become one
Park Soo Kyung left
He's tired of the palace
Now he
afraid of me
Do you want to know whose name the late emperor wrote in the last decree?
Right?
Wondering if I stole this throne or not
I don't think about it at all
I'm the least curious about this
It was empty there
There was no name there
Therefore
I tore up the decree, thinking that it would cause even more confusion
One way or another, we have already captured the palace
You did everything right
Park Soo Kyung left
Baek Ah sees me only as an emperor,
not my brother
For Choi Chi Mon I
avenger of the death of his older brother
Jeong...
sees me as a murderer of my own brothers. That's right,
even my mother
thinks I'm a thief
You were right
Throne
makes you scared and lonely
I'm here
Do you remember: I love, I love
I won't leave you
In your eyes, I settled in your gaze
And I can only answer you:
Hold me if I'm swinging
my love
Wow! This is what Jeongdeokjeong looks like!
I have a favor to ask of you, madam.
By order of the new emperor,
free some court ladies
Including me
I was told to leave Damiwon
I think I won't be able to see you often
Where will you go?
Madam, can you help me stay in the palace?
Please ask the emperor for this
How did it go?
She said she would ask the emperor
Excellent
You should stay in Damiwon
But this chance...
May I come with you, your highness?
I don't know when else I'll get the chance to leave the palace.
Chae Ryung, you can still do a lot for me while in the palace.
When the time comes I'll take you away from here
A request for independence means
that Jeonju will no longer be part of Goryeo?
Your right to the throne is in doubt
How can we perceive you as an emperor?
Loyalty comes only from trust
I am also the grandson of Mr. Yoo Geun Dal
However, the entire clan is against me, the current emperor?
You have to consider what other clans will think,
when even the emperor's clan does not support him
Do you want
break our ties, Jeong?
If the problem with the late emperor's wishes becomes clear,
we'll find out for sure
We have to do something about the Yu Clan, otherwise things will get worse
Or they must show them the last decree of the emperor,
or enter into an alliance with other powerful clans
Until the very end
I'm not her son
Wu Hee?
I'm sure the emperor will like it
Isn't it a small gift compared to the new chambers?
Su,
if I hurt someone for my own happiness,
this harm will eventually come back to me, right?
I'll never be forgiven
That's right
You don't have to harm anyone to save yourself.
However...
I think you and I deserve some leniency
We've been through a lot
Scars on our wrists...
We just want a piece of happiness
which is barely enough to cover the scars
I think we deserve forgiveness
even if we behave a little selfishly
I'll believe in it
Could you bring this to my chambers?
Yes
In the end you went to him
You said that wanting both you and the throne is greed
Now you are the emperor's woman
How can I accept this?
He was honest with me
He told me he didn't want to lose me or the throne
He admitted everything, even his greed
I had no choice, I tried to understand
I've always been interested
Why did you insist that I cannot be emperor?
In your eyes...
Didn't I look worthy?
- That's not true
- What then?
It is said that Prince Wang So was born under the emperor's star.
Emperor Taejo knew about this too
It's not your fault
This is the natural course of things, fate
Emperor's Star?
All because of some star?
The natural course of things?
Fate?
When I see you I
I can’t breathe, I’m timid
It's as if everything in the world has stopped
Can you promise me?
If I pass by like a breeze,
That you'll never take it off?
you won't even notice
My heart is all given to you
But loving you is very painful for me
And so sad
I need to cross you out of my heart
It's not your fault
so hard
This is the natural course of things, fate
Don't forget, please!
That eternal love
mine
You will become an empress
Will you help me?
Nobody can have everything
Would that be fair?
It happened that I would reach the very sources of the stream,
Sitting down, I contemplate how the clouds rise in the distance
Done
Why did you need me to write so much?
I have a reason for this
You said that there would be something prepared for me in your chambers
It was just rice
You ate it without leaving a grain
I was going to give some to Baek Ah and astronomer Chi Mon
You don't have to think about anyone but me
It's all mine
Did something happen today?
No, why do you think that?
You smile more than usual
I'm worried, that's all
Don't try to know everything about me
If you keep acting like this when we're not even married, I'm going to want to run away.
It's because I've been waiting all day for you, Your Majesty.
Can I work in Damiwon during the day?
Even if I can't serve myself,
there are many other things I can do
And regarding Chae Ryung...
I heard she was released from her job in Damiwon
Can you let her stay?
She has nowhere to go even if she leaves the palace
Chae Ryung?
I don't know
I need her so I don't feel alone
Huh? A?
Okay, okay
But... I don't think you'll be lonely in the future
We will need to give birth to children and raise them
D-children?
The doctor will come to examine you
You need to take care of your physical health to have children.
We're not even married yet
And you tell me to take care of my health and think about the children
Marriage? We can get married
When should we do this?
Let's get married whenever you want
No I don't want to
Am I not only in your heart?
Don't you want to?
You need to make me an offer
If I can do what I want
You wanted to talk to me near the prayer towers
I don't have to worry and wait
Do you think I'm stupid?
I want to make you mine
You were going to propose to me there, weren't you?
I don't know when I can get there
Now it's not so easy for me to leave the palace
Clear
Should I propose so that you will be satisfied and marry me?
I always laugh just like that, remembering you
It's harder to do business with you,
than to decide the state
I wonder if love has come to me?
Even the sun and the moon
They don't know my feelings
To be with you
Whatever you want to say
can you be honest with me
I will tell everything to the emperor myself.
Your knee still hasn't healed
He was not treated properly after the torture, it developed into a chronic illness
One day you may lose the ability to walk
Clear
I'll be careful
However, there is something worse than this
Rapid heartbeat
Rapid heartbeat?
When you are stressed or scared,
do you feel pressure in the chest area?
Have you ever felt out of breath
to the point of fainting?
Well, yes...
You are very depressed
The illness of your soul has become a physical illness
Now I can't say for sure
how long will you live
Can't you vouch?
Will I not live long?
I'm fine
Please tell me how long I can live
Now I will take good care of my health
But I'm only in my 20s
The most is 10 years
I'll live a little longer
With him...
I want to stay with him a little longer
What do you want so badly?
Praying that So will remain on the throne for a long time?
I ask that the brave and kind 14th Prince become my friend again
You said you never
you won't take anyone's side
However, you took the side of my 4th brother
I feel betrayed
Don't misdirect your anger
Have you forgotten what the last emperor did to your elder brother and the 10th prince?
It was obvious that So would become emperor
Yeah, you must be right
But I still think that everything has gone completely wrong since Seo came to Songak
The struggle for the throne has always existed
As soon as So entered it,
she became even more confused and ruthless
Besides, the truth is that he stole the throne
I'm worried that everyone will be in danger
Don't you think you can become an empress?
Empress?
I don't know
I haven't thought about it properly
The Empress must use her clan and other clans to support the Emperor
This is why Emperor Taejo had so many marriages
Under these conditions, you will be just one of the emperor's many women.
Is this how you wanted to live your life?
What about camel riding in the desert?
and travel to the ocean to distant lands?
Isn't this what you were talking about?
When you get tired of this place, tell me
If you really want to leave...
I know the way
I'll remember this
Emperor, the 8th Prince wishes to see you
Say what you want
I am here on behalf of all your subjects
Can you imagine them?
First
As for the leader of the 300,000-strong army,
they would like to be the only ones
who has the right to vote for who they will be
Second
Needless to say, they will also levy a tax on grain
If you let every area
collect taxes due to the palace,
you won't sit here alone like you do now
So, distancing me from the army and the treasury,
you want to cut off both the emperor's wings
If you thought trying to put pressure on me like this would work,
you were wrong
If you don't want to lose your wings...
What about your heart?
Your Majesty, Hwangbo Clan of Hwangju
wanted to ask for marriage with you
Beautiful chambers
You arranged everything perfectly
Please tell me what you came for
I will listen to you, but only today
I didn't come to fight
I want to clarify what each of us wants
I didn't think there was anything we could give or take from each other
I don't need anything from you, princess
You can stay here if you want
I recognize you as the emperor's woman
Still, you will not become a noble concubine
I'm not going to be interested in who will take care of the emperor day and night
I don't understand
what do you want to say
Honor and recognition - that's what I want
I also want to see my son on the throne
I will marry the emperor
I will become his wife
I will be the empress
If you marry Yong Hwa,
all clans will be on your side
The Hwangbo clan will be your support
Don't try to shake me like that
Yes, I'm sitting on the throne
but I still have the temperament of a wolfhound
You occupy a position that is hard to get and even harder to defend.
Sitting on the throne, you will clearly understand
that powerful clans are both good and bad at the same time
If you want to sit on the throne for a long time,
you need these families to be on your side
I promised to marry someone else
Do you mean Hae Soo?
This girl can't become empress
If I said I would...
I'll do it
You must have forgotten
To avoid marriage with Emperor Taejo,
she cut her hand
A woman with a scar on her body...
cannot become the emperor's wife
Thanks for watching with us!
Release group MANIA
http://doramamania.mybb.ru
http://vk.com/doramamania
Scarlet Hearts: Ryeo
You must defend your throne
I will make our son the next emperor
How dare he use the throne as bait and play with me?
You may suddenly pass by and not notice, have you forgotten me?
You can't go anywhere
You are my only empress
But until you remember me, I will wait for you
Please refuse to marry the emperor
You have to let him go first
What should I do?
I ended up becoming a monster in Su's eyes
At the same time, in the same place we will always be
I will never forgive him for this